本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
湮灭之日  第四天
末日将至
乡亲们  末日已经到来
End times are here, folks.
唯一的救赎方式只有拥抱我们至高霸主三角一般的生活
Only way to salvation is to embrace the triangular ways of our overlord.
任何多于三条边的物体都是罪恶的
Any object with more than three sides is sinful.
这就行了  比尔应该会喜欢
That's it. That's probably what Bill wants.
看来我的信仰一直是个谎言啊
I reckon I've been living a lie.
女士们先生们
Ladies, gentlemen,
还有那个长着大概八十七张脸的家伙
that creature with, like, 87 different faces.
有八十八张脸呢
Eighty-eight different faces.
不好意思  别那么小心眼啊
Oh, sorry. Touchy subject.
总之还是很愉快的  我们把重力泉搅得天翻地覆
Anyways, it's been fun turning Gravity Falls inside out,
把镇上吓坏的居民驱赶到一起
rounding up all its terrified citizens
将他们垒成这个凝结人类痛苦的巨大王座
and then stacking them into this massive throne of frozen human agony.
别担心  他们已经失去意识了
Don't worry, they're not conscious anymore.
应该吧
Probably.
我的鸡蛋饼  看起来可面善了
My omelets... they have friendly faces.
哎  别乱动  回去
Whoops. Back you go there.
但是重力泉仅仅是一个开端
But Gravity Falls is just the beginning.
是时候把混乱带到全世界了
It's time to take our chaos worldwide!
准备好  小伙子们  走遍天涯海角
All right, boys, to the corners of the earth.
用这般怪诞引燃世界吧
Set the world aflame with your weirdness.
这个时空归我们了
This dimension is ours!
啊  全球统治
Ah, global domination.
我很快就会习惯
I could get used to...
什么
What?!
嗯  这可能没我想得那么简单
Hm, this might be more complicated than I thought.
我好像把哪儿摔断了
I think I broke something.
忍一下会死啊
Walk it off!
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
时间轴： WaitinZ  Enpistu
翻译： 战忽局副局座  Wizard小希  moonywen
怪诞小镇  第二季第十九集
Gravity Falls  S02E19  Weirdmageddon Part 2 Escape From Reality
■
校订  后期： Enpistu  WaitinZ
梅宝  梅宝
Mabel. Mabel!
好了  各位  比尔掌控了全镇
Okay, guys, Bill has taken over the town,
如果这般怪诞继续传播
and if this weirdness spreads,
整个世界都要遭殃了
he's gonna take over the whole world.
想阻止他  我们首先要救出梅宝
Our first step to stopping him is rescuing Mabel,
但是他把梅宝关在这个奇怪的泡泡牢笼里
but he's got her trapped in this strange prison bubble.
这到底是哪里啊
What is this place anyway?
伙计们  就算是个死  我也要死在拥抱中
Guys, if I die, I wanna die hugging.
苏斯  我喘不过气了
Soos, you're choking me.
让我来当你们的肉垫吧
Let my body be your shield.
整个地面是个充气城堡
Is the entire ground a bouncy castle?
听到八十年代的歌了吗
Do you hear '80s music?
空气中是不是有童话世界的味道
And does the air smell like childlike wonder?
这就是梅宝的监狱
This is Mabel's prison?
确定  一定  肯定
Yes. Definitely. Absolutely.
到点了  该疯玩了  各位
It's fun o'clock, everyone.
今日天气大部有彩虹  局部地区开舞会
Today's weather calls for rainbows with a chance of dance parties.
如果你是戴着大礼帽独角兽的主人
If you're the owner of a unicorn with a top hat,
请立刻前往冰激凌海滩
please come to the ice cream beach.
你的独角兽就要拖走了
Your unicorn is being towed.
这个新世界是怎么回事
What is this new world?
亮晶晶  闪光光  太豪华了
Shining, shimmering, splendid.
欢迎来到梅宝乐园
Welcome to Mabeland.
梅宝乐园
<i>Mabeland</i>
这简直比世界末日更可怕
And this is worse than the apocalypse.
天啊  我的眼睛要被闪瞎了
Dude, this place hurts my eyes.
瞎眼很正常
Oh, that's normal.
梅宝乐园彩虹的某些颜色
Mabeland's rainbows have colors
只有蜜蜂和学艺术的能看见
only bees and art students can see.
现在谁想去城市大环游啊
Now who wants to go on the grand tour?
-有得选吗  -没得选
- Do we have a choice? - No!
梅宝乐园是终极天堂
Mabeland is the ultimate paradise,
唯一的规矩就是  无拘无束
and the only rule-- there are no rules!
除了一条高压线一般的规矩
Except for one rule, which is very serious.
不过从来也没人犯过
But no one would ever break it,
所以说不说也就不重要了
so it's not worth mentioning.
听好了  梦幻怪男生  我们可不是来玩的
Listen, creepy dream guys, we're not here to party, okay?
我们是来找梅宝  救她出去的
We just need to find Mabel and get her out of here.
她到底在哪儿
Where is she?
我们的梅宝女神就在下一站
Our home girl Mabel lives at our next stop.
赞爆了
That rules!
快来尝尝酷炫企鹅端上的超赞零食吧
Now come have rad snacks served by awesome penguins.
太棒了  我都饿死了
Oh, score. I'm so hungry.
对啊  连续三天
Yeah. I haven't eaten anything
我除了啃了几口帽子啥都没吃了
except for part of my hat for the last three days.
你们能不能先等一下
Can you guys just hold on a second?
难道看不出发生了什么吗
Do you see what's happening here?
别忘了  这个世界是比尔创造的
Don't forget, this world was created by Bill.
这饮料说不定是鲜血
That punch is probably blood.
闪光雨点说不定是磨成粉的骨头或婴儿什么的
And that glitter rain is probably ground-up bones or babies or something.
比尔利用梅宝的幻想创造了这些变态陷阱
Bill's using Mabel's own fantasies as some sick trap.
我们必须找到梅宝  把她救出这个鬼地方
We need to grab Mabel and get the heck outta here.
梅宝  她就在那座最高的塔顶上
Oh, Mabel? She's at the top of the tallest tower,
由又大又软的华夫饼卫兵把守着
guarded by those big, buff waffle guards.
要想过他们这关可不容易
There's no way to get past them.
谁给我拿瓶糖浆
Someone hand me some syrup.
养兵千日  用兵一时  命运来召唤啦
It's happening. The moment we trained for.
别怕  哥们儿  有我呢
Don't worry, man. I gotcha.
伙计们  机会来了
It's now or never, guys.
人质救援
This is a rescue.
所有人都趴下
Everyone hit the deck.
梅宝  坚持住
Hang in there, Mabel!
她在那儿
There she is.
苏斯  带上她
Soos, grab her.
温蒂  把门堵好
Wendy, barricade the door.
小公主  该走了
Up you go, little lady.
苏斯  温蒂  迪普
Soos? Wendy? Dipper?
松饼卫兵回来了
The waffles are coming back.
-别磨磨蹭蹭了  -呃  各位
- We gotta hurry! - Uh, guys.
别担心  梅宝  我们会把你救出去的
Don't worry, Mabel. We'll get you out of this.
但是迪普
But Dipper...
梅宝  你在干嘛啊
Mabel, what are you doing?
我们要把你从监狱救出去呢
We're trying to save you from this prison.
这不是监狱
This isn't a prison.
这个世界是我创造的
I made this world.
我在这里醒过来
Well, I sorta woke up here.
-这事说来话长  -你在说什么呢
- It's complicated. - What are you saying?
我是说现在这儿就是我的家
I'm saying this is my home now,
梅宝市长
我不想被救出去
and I don't wanna be saved.
-抱歉  梅宝  -没关系  泡泡熊
- Sorry, Mabel. - No worries, bubble bear.
-你干了什么  -听着  听到你说
- You did what?! - Look, after you said
暑假结束后不会跟我回家
you wouldn't come back home with me at the end of the summer
要留下来当什么徒弟
for your "apprenticeship,"
我恨不得躲在毛衣里过一辈子算了
I wanted to hide in my sweater forever.
但是我醒来之后  发现这个地方
But then I woke up in a place that gives me
给了我想要的一切
exactly what I wanted--
永远不用长大的无尽夏日
an endless summer where we'll never have to grow up.
在这里  阳光永远明媚  宴会永不散席
Here, the sun shines all day, the party never ends,
现在你们也来了  一切终于完美了
and now that you guys are here, it's finally perfect.
听着  梅宝  我们不是来享乐的
Listen, Mabel, we're not here to party.
这一切太疯狂了
All of this is crazy.
唉  就知道你会这么说  迪普
Ugh! I figured<i> you</i> might say something like that, Dipper.
所以我创造了个态度更积极的
That's why I've prepared a backup Dipper
备胎版迪普
with a more supportive attitude.
早啊  哥们儿姐们儿都吃了吧
Wiggity-wiggity what's up, dude bros?
在下小鲜肉迪迪
I'm Dippy Fresh.
我喜欢玩滑板  无条件支持姐姐
I like skateboarding, supporting my sister,
说三句话就击掌一次
and punctuating every third sentence with a high five.
那我就不客
Oh, don't mind if I...
不好意思  不能让他把手一直举着
I'm sorry. I can't leave him hanging.
好嘞
Yes.
苏斯  咱们友尽了
You're dead to me, Soos.
相信我吧  你们会爱死这个地方的
Trust me. You guys are gonna love it here.
这个世界总是了解你的愿望
This world always knows what you want,
甚至能先你一步满足愿望
sometimes even before you do.
毛丝鼠  我当然想要啦
Apparently I wanted a chinchilla.
梅宝乐园又猜对了
Right again, Mabeland.
梅宝  你自己想想这疯不疯狂
Mabel, listen to yourself. This is crazy.
我们闹矛盾是我不对
I'm sorry about our fight,
我也很抱歉现在很多事情不能如愿
and I'm sorry things aren't great right now,
但这不代表你能在这里永远躲下去
but that doesn't mean you can just stay in here forever.
别上火  吃点镇静剂  就长在树上
Hey, take a chill pill. Those grow on trees here.
小鲜肉你别瞎掺和
You stay out of this, Dippy Fresh!
哥们儿  淡定
Dude, calm down.
小鲜肉迪迪又没招惹你
Dippy Fresh didn't do anything to you, dawg.
我知道这个地方太过美好不像是真的
I know it seems too good to be true,
但是凡事要亲身体验嘛
but just give this place a chance.
梅宝乐园知你心中所想
Mabeland knows just what you want,
永远满足你的需要
and always provides.
布丁夹心的  太棒了
Pudding center. Nice.
其实呢  梅宝  这件事上我跟迪普想的一样
Actually, Mabel, I'm with Dipper on this.
重力泉碰到麻烦了  而且我真的觉得
Gravity Falls is in trouble, and I really think--
温蒂
Wendy!
伙计们  你们没事
Guys? You're safe.
我们弄到一辆装满烟花和假身份证的怪兽卡车
We've got a monster truck full of fireworks, fake ID's,
还有恶作剧用品
and pranking supplies.
想把这卡车开到学校去
Wanna drive this truck to the high school
把皮揣子粘到校长头上吗
and glue this plunger to the principal's head?
想啊  太想了
Yes. Yes, I do.
抱歉  伙计们  我一直都想这么干来着
Sorry, guys. I've always wanted to do that.
我去去就来
I'll be back in just a few minutes.
-温蒂  -别担心  伙计
- Wendy? - Don't worry, dude.
这世上没有什么能阻挡我
There's nothing in this world that could break me
执行咱们的任务
from our mission.
苏斯  我的好儿子  我回来了
Soos<i> mi hijo.</i> I have returned.
天啊  等等  老爸
Holy... whoa, whoa. Dad?
因为你也不记得我长得什么样了
You don't remember what I look like,
所以我拥有专业摔跤手的身体
so I have the body of a pro wrestler,
还长着你在辣酱瓶上看见的脸
and a face you once saw on a hot sauce bottle.
我没能陪在你身边
I was never there for you,
但是在这个世界里  我可以陪你了
but in this world, I can be.
-你真是太完美了  -这是个陷阱
- You're perfect. - It's a trap.
别跟他走  苏斯  不管他答应给你什么
Don't go with him, Soos, no matter what he offers you.
想玩接球吗
Want to play catch?
抱歉了  伙计
I'm sorry, dude.
就算这只是梦一场
Even if it is all a dream,
我也得玩完这个游戏
I've gotta play just one game.
走吧  老爹
Come on, Dad.
行了  这有点太过分了
Okay, this has gone too far.
你该不会真觉得沉迷于这些幻想对他们有益吧
You can't honestly think these fantasies are good for anyone.
这结果是无可非议的
You can't argue with the results.
人们在这里生活得很快乐
People are happy here.
或真或假真的很重要吗
Does it really matter if it's real or not?
就这一次  别再用脑子思考了
For once, stop listening to your head,
随心所愿吧
and listen to your heart.
在梅宝乐园里  每个人都能找到自己想要的  就连你也是
Mabeland has something for everyone, even you.
其实呢
In fact...
不要  我不看  我不看
Nope. Not looking. Not looking.
行了  谁能跟我说说
All right, can anybody explain to me why,
为什么即使我们有了无限能量
even with our newfound infinite power...
也没人逃得出这个
none of us can escape the borders
小破镇的边界
of this stupid hick town?!
有种力量把我们困在了这里
There's some kind of force field keeping us in.
但是谁能知道怎么补救呢
But who would know how to fix it?
看来某人得重新上岗了
Hmm. Maybe someone needs to come out of retirement.
比尔  抱歉  老大
Bill. Sorry, boss,
但是吉迪恩让派恩斯家的人逃掉了
but Gideon let the Pines family escape.
他们现在正在梅宝的泡泡里
They're inside Mabel's bubble as we speak.
伙计  梅宝的泡泡是我创建出的最邪恶的陷阱
Buddy, Mabel's bubble is the most diabolical trap I've ever created.
要使出洪荒之力
It would take a will of titanium
才能不向它的诱惑屈服
not to give into its temptations.
把吉迪恩给我抓来  剩下的时间可以休息了
Fetch me Gideon, and take the rest of the day off.
真是越来越好玩了
Things just got a little more interesting.
我是个毛绒玩具树
Bo-ba-do-do, I'm a stuffed animal tree
他是个毛绒玩具树
He's a stuffed animal tree
就算打个水漂也这么完美
Even my stone skips are perfect.
我逗谁呢
Who am I kidding?
也许梅宝是对的
Maybe Mabel's right.
外面是个恐怖的世界
It's a horror show out there.
至少这里的空气还可以呼吸
At least the air here is breathable.
伙计  你在跟河说话呢
Dude, you're talking to a river.
嗨  温蒂  你怎么样了
Oh, hey, Wendy. What's up?
我还以为你忙着砸学校什么的呢
I thought you were busy wrecking the school or whatever.
那个啊  不一会就玩腻了
Yeah, that got old quick.
这破音乐真是要把我弄崩溃了
And this music is really starting to get on my nerves.
我觉得你对这个地方的看法是正确的
I think that stuff you said about this place is right.
真的吗  那咱们现在只需要个计划
Really? Well, now we just need a plan.
别担心  你总能想出好主意
Don't worry. You always think of something.
你知道吗  你比其他任何人都聪明得多
You know, you're so much smarter than, like, everyone else.
说来挺有意思的
It's kinda funny.
你要是年龄再大一点的话  可能就是我的梦中情人了
If you were older, you'd be, like, my dream guy.
等等  你这话是真心的吗
Wait. Do you really mean that?
等等
Wait a minute.
在这个地方  你想多大就多大
In this place, you can be any age you want.
咱们要是同岁的话  你和我也许就能
If we were the same age, maybe you and me could...
谁知道呢  真的在一起了
I don't know... actually be together.
等等  真的吗
Wait. Really?
我敢说只要去找梅宝  她现在就能让咱们在一起
I bet if we asked Mabel, she could do it right now.
在这个世界里  就我们俩长相厮守
In this place, it could finally be just you and me.
来吧  伙计  牵着我的手
Come on, man. Just take my hand.
等等  这不是真的
Wait. This isn't real!
你不该这么做的  迪普
You shouldn't have done that, Dipper!
我们一直在盯着你
We're watching you.
这里到处都是眼线
There are eyes everywhere.
-嗨  迪普  -嗨  迪普
- Hi, Dipper. - Hey, Dipper.
- Hey, Dipper. - Hey, Dipper.
我是个毛绒玩具树
Bo-ba-do-do, I'm a stuffed animal tree
哦  天啊
Oh, my gosh.
实在是太疯狂了
This is crazy.
我要疯了
I'm losing my mind.
我们一定要逃出这里
We have to get out of here.
一定要回到现实世界里
We have to go back... to the real world!
以橡皮鸭笑脸条款的名义
Under Article Smiley Face of Exhibit Squeaky Duck,
你被正式指控违反这里唯一的规矩
you are hereby accused of breaking our one rule--
提到现实世界
mentioning reality.
准备被这个世界永远驱逐吧
Prepare to be banished from this land forever!
梅宝  你不至于做出这种傻事吧
Mabel, you're smarter than this.
比尔一定是给你洗脑了吧
Bill has you hypnotized or something.
你真的任他们就这样驱逐我吗
Are you really gonna let them banish me?
不  当然不了
No. Of course not.
那是我弟弟  伙计们
That's my brother, guys.
肯定有商量的余地的
There's gotta be another way.
行吧
Very well.
要是迪普想留下的话
If Dipper wishes to stay,
他必须在幻想对抗现实一案的终极审判中为自己辩护
he must plead his case in the ultimate trial of<i> Fantasy vs. Reality.</i>
喂  没搞错吧
Hey. Seriously?
是他干的
It was him.
没搞错吧  梅宝
Seriously, Mabel?
你真想让他们把咱们的争吵闹到法庭上来吗
You're letting them take our argument to court?
喂  梅宝乐园的规矩又不是我定的
Hey, I didn't make the rules of Mabeland.
是你定的  墙上还有个你制定法律的织锦呢
Yes, you did. There's a tapestry of you making the rules.
全体起立  有请大法官  大脸凯蒂喵施瓦茨斯坦因
All rise for the Honorable Judge Kitty Kitty Meow Meow Face Schwartzstein.
肃静  肃静
Order, order.
审判现在就开始喵
This trial begins right meow.
嗯  法官
Ahem. Judge?
抱歉  抱歉
Sorry, sorry.
我们今天来审判迪普・派恩斯的
We are here to try Dipper Pines
“幻想对抗现实”一案
in the case of <i>Fantasy vs. Reality.</i>
如果迪普赢了  梅宝就跟他回去
If Dipper wins, Mabel will return with him
回到现实世界
to the real world.
但如果他输了的话  就会被永远放逐
But if he loses, he will be banished forever,
由人见人爱的小鲜肉迪迪来接替他的位置
and replaced with town darling Dippy Fresh.
迪迪  亮个相
Dippy, come on out.
翻滚吧迪迪
Flippy dip dip.
我真是恨死他了
I hate him so much.
最终判决将取决于你们陪审团同伴的意见
The final decision will be made by a jury of your peers.
你好啊  好喜欢你的发带
Hi there. I love your headband.
别说了  是我喜欢你的发带才对
Shut your mouth. I love your headband.
咱们居然有一样的发带
We're all wearing the same headband.
哈哈  发带
Ha ha! Headband!
听着  梅宝  这一切简直荒唐透顶
Look, Mabel, this whole thing is ridiculous.
但如果只有赢了这场审判才能带你回家
But if winning a trial is what it takes to get you to come home with us,
那就来吧
then so be it.
抱歉  迪普  但我现在只能通过我的法律团队发言了
I'm sorry, Dipper, but I can only speak through my legal team now.
在英俊魁梧这方面我们可是拿到了博士学位呢
We have a doctorate degree in hunkiness.
还有打击犯罪和国际法也是啦
Also criminal and international law.
来听听开庭陈述
Let's hear opening statements.
尊敬的法官大人  乡亲们
Your Honor, townsfolk,
陪审团的可爱女士们
lovely ladies of the jury.
哦  他是在说我们呢
Oh, he's talking about us.
好可爱哦
That's lovely.
案情很简单
My case is simple.
这个罪孽深重的家伙认为现实比幻想更好
This very unrighteous dude thinks that reality is better than fantasy.
但现实是虚伪的  无聊的  伤人的
But reality is bogus, lame, and whack.
反对  法官大人  这些都只是猜测
Objection, Your Honor. That's conjecture.
喵对无效
Meow-verruled!
我来给各位展示一下迪普所钟爱的“现实”
I'd like to show you this "reality" that Dipper loves so much.
看看它为我的委托人和迪普的人生
Show you how it has wronged my client, and Dipper,
带来了何等伤害
their entire lives.
证据一
Exhibit "A."
梅宝的剪贴簿
Mabel's scrapbook.
二年级  十月十日
Second grade, October 10.
拍照日
Photo day.
过敏真讨厌
Darn allergies.
搞定  第一百万个啪啪圈
Boom! A million slap bracelets.
我要拍出史上最棒的照片
I'm gonna have the best photo ever.
喜欢我新编的小辫子吗
And how do you like my new pigtails?
玩开心点  小屁孩
Have fun, brat.
你毁了我的头发
You ruined my hair!
迪普  我该怎么办
Dipper, what do I do?
呃  我  我也不知
Um, I... well... I don't...
梅宝
Mabel!
梅宝幻想着拍一张漂亮的校园纪念照
Mabel's fantasy was having a great school photo,
但在现实里却未能如愿
but reality had other plans.
喂  那天只是碰巧很糟糕
Look, that was one bad day.
这只是其中之一  二月十四日  四年级
One of many. February 14, fourth grade.
-情人节  -拜托  你不能
- Valentine's Day. - Oh, come on, man. You can't...
迪普  你收到了几张情人节卡片
How many Valentines did you get, Dipper?
哈哈  迪普什么也没收到
Oh, hey, Dipper didn't get any.
天啊  我还以为我才是班级潘
Oh, man, I thought I was the class loser.
各位  光棍迪一张情人节卡片也没有
Hey, everyone, Dipstick didn't get any.
真不敢相信他是你弟弟
I can't believe that kid's your brother.
嘿  说这些有什么意义呢
Hey, what's the point of all this?
都是过去的事了
That was in the past.
你的生活变得更好了吗  老兄
Is your life any better now, bro?
心碎  失败  违约
Heartbreak, disaster, broken promises.
这才是你的现实
That's reality for you.
在外面  除了心碎你一无所有
Out there, it's nothing but heartbreak.
但是在这里  谁想吃哈巴狗圣代
But in here, who wants pug sundaes?
给我一个麦克风  塞勒
Hand me a microphone, Xyler.
太合理了  老兄
Totally righteous, bro.
-我们是兄弟吗  -你说呢
- Are we brothers? - I don't know.
看来我们可以作出判决了
I think we're ready for a verdict.
等一下  我还没陈述我的辩词呢
Wait! I haven't even presented my case.
你还有什么可说的
Do you even have a case?
是的  我有  法官大人
Yes, I do, Your Honor.
我申请传唤证人梅宝・派恩斯
I call as a witness Mabel Pines.
呃  反对
Uh, objection?
申请有效
I'll allow it.
我们猫咪好奇心重  喵喵
Us cats are famously curious, meow meow.
梅宝  听着
Mabel, listen.
也许我无法解决所有问题
I might not have all the answers.
我不够有型  也不够酷
I'm not stylish, and I'm not cool,
我也不能凭空变出哈巴狗圣代
and I can't make pugs appear out of thin air.
-嘘  -有罪
- Boo! - Guilty!
但我很了解一个人  那就是你
But I know one thing well, and that's you,
我知道虽然你表面上好像很喜欢这里
and I know that even though you might act like it,
但其实并不想留在这个幻想世界
you don't wanna be in this fantasy world.
呃  好吧  你说得对
Uh... pssshh! Yeah, right.
你害怕长大
You're scared of growing up.
这是无可厚非的
And who could blame you?
我也很害怕
I'm scared, too.
啦啦啦啦啦啦啦  我听不见
Uh... la la la la la la la! I'm not listening.
守卫  手指堵耳朵
Guards, the fingers.
听着  现实生活有时候确实很讨人厌
Look, real life stinks sometimes, okay?
我不打算撒谎
I'm not gonna lie.
但比起否定现实  我们还有更好的方式渡过难关
There's a better way to get through it than denial,
那就是从关心你的人那里寻求帮助
and that's with help from people who care about you.
我们一直以来都是这么过来的
It's how we've gotten through our whole lives.
看看吧
Just look.
梅宝  我有办法拯救你的照片了
Mabel, I figured out a way to fix your photo.
什么办法  你有假发吗
What? You have a wig?
没  但我有个剃刀
No, but I have a razor.
你真是疯了
You're crazy.
致我最爱的弟弟
我们总是相互扶持
We've always been there for each other.
梅宝  我总以为是你一直生活在幻想里
Mabel, I thought you were living a fantasy,
但看看我
but look at me.
居然真的想过要留在这里
I actually thought I was gonna stay here
成为阿福的徒弟
and be Ford's apprentice.
将大好青春的时光都禁锢在地下室里的实验服中
Spend my entire teens cooped up in a basement with a lab coat.
这该有多可笑啊
How ridiculous is that?
我不知道未来会发生什么
I don't know what's gonna happen in the future,
但无论发生什么  你都不要害怕
but whatever it is, you don't have to fear,
因为我们会一起面对
because we'll do it together.
我不会接受阿福的收徒邀请
I'm not taking Ford's apprenticeship.
我们历经千难万险才找到你
We've traveled to heck and back to get you,
我们要一起回去
and we're going back together.
离开这个幻想世界
Leave this fantasy world.
我们一起打败比尔  一起长大吧
Let's beat Bill and grow up together.
肃静  法庭内保持肃静
Order. Order in the court!
见鬼  这锤子怎么敲起来吱吱叫
Dang it, why is this hammer squeaking?!
你说真的
You mean it?
你真的愿意和我一起回家吗
You're really coming home with me?
确定  一定
Yes. Definitely.
肯定
Absolutely.
褰愕鼙П
Awkward sibling hug?
不要这么做
Don't do it!
你要是这么做  一切就全完了
You do this, and it's all over.
真诚姐弟抱抱
Sincere sibling hug.
不要拍背
Don't do the pats!
拍拍
Pat, pat.
噢  天啊
Oh, man.
我从没注意过这地方原来有这么亮
I never noticed how bright this place is.
我是不是一整周都在听
Ugh! Have I actually been listening to the same song
同一首歌
for an entire week?
该让你冷静一下了
Whoa, time to calm you down.
呃  怎么不管用了
Uh, why isn't this working?
因为你对这个地方的统治结束了
Because your reign over this land is over!
我们得快点出去
We gotta get outta here.
苏斯  温蒂  乐园关门了
Soos, Wendy, Paradise is cancelled.
所有人上来
Everyone get on.
带我们冲向自由吧  巨型摇摇
Take us to freedom, Giant Waddles. Yeah!
好了  大家都准备好了吗
All right, guys, are you ready for this?
对不起了  梅宝乐园
Sorry, Mabeland.
是时候戳破你这个大泡泡了
It's time to burst your bubble.
你还好吗  大家都还好吗
You all good? Everyone good?
我们都很想你  梅宝
We've missed you, Mabel.
迪普  我很感激你在里面所说的一切
Hey, Dipper, I appreciate what you said back there.
但如果你想接受阿福的收徒邀请
But if you wanna take Ford's apprenticeship,
我也不会拦着你
I won't get in your way.
打算让我错过你尴尬的青春期吗
Pfft. Miss out on your awkward teen years?
你想得美
You wish.
天啊  我在里面疯掉了
Man, I went nuts back there.
我是说  拜托  现实世界才没那么糟糕呢  对吧
I mean, come on, the real world can't be that bad, right?
我的天
Oh, boy.
-大家都去哪儿了  -小镇荒废了
- Where is everyone? - The town's deserted.
比尔已经赢了吗
Did Bill already win?
走吧  伙计们  看看我们能不能躲在神秘小屋里
Come on, guys. Let's see if we can go hide out in the shack.
太好了  它和我们离开时一样破
Yes! It's in shambles just like we left it.
真不敢相信  这是我第一次这么开心能去上班
Oh, man, this is the first time I've ever felt happy going to work.
你好房子  你好门廊
Hello, house. Hello, porch.
你好  我粘在沙发上的口香糖
Hello, wads of gum I left stuck to the couch.
等等  什么声音
Wait. What was that?
大伙  干掉他们
Let's get 'em, dudes.
-斯坦  -孩子们
- Stan? - Kids?
就想告诉大家  卫生纸用完了
Just so everyone knows, we're out of toilet paper.
我错过了什么剧情吗
Did I miss something?
我们还活着
Whoa, we survived.
但这是在哪儿
But where are we?
我们是真实的吗
Are we real?
这里是现实吗
Is this reality?
让-保罗・萨特曾经提出
Jean-Paul Sartre postulated that
一切存在都是毫无道理地出生
every existing thing is born without reason,
（注：引自萨特小说《恶心》）
因软弱而延续
prolongs itself out of weakness,
因偶然而死亡
and dies by chance.
太合理了  老兄
Totally righteous, bro.
我知道
I know!